Guide to the William Blathwayt Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1646-1796; Series I; 4.0' (10 boxes)
  - Vernon, James, 1646-1727
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jun 2 (Box 9, Folder 199)
      Sending letters and a warrant for a baronetcy for Prendergast, with a query if the King had ordered it. 1. Prendergast, Thomas, Sir, 1660?-1709.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jun 6
      Enclosing a second and correct warrant for Prendergast to be a baronet in Ireland. 1. Prendergast, Thomas, Sir, 1660?-1709.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jun 9
      Forwarding letters.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jun 13
      Concerning a possible pension of £100 p.a. for M. d'Arselliers on the Irish establishment, and a special dispensation for a kinsman of Lord Coningsby to continue his studies at Dublin. 1. Arselliers, Gaspard Perrinet Arselliers, Marquis of. 2. Coningsby, Thomas Coningsby, Earl, 1656?-1729.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jun 16
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jun 20
      Concerning one Plowman, an Englishman in Italy.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jun 23
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jun 27 (Box 9, Folder 199)
      Concerning the dispensation for Lord Coningsby's kinsmen in Dublin. 1. Coningsby, Thomas Coningsby, Earl, 1656?-1725.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jun 30
      Forwarding a copy of Sir William Beeston's proclamation against assisting the Scots at Darien. 1. Beeston, William, Sir, fl. 1702.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jul 4
      Vernon will send a copy of Beeston's proclamation against the Scots in Darien to Stanhope to help settle differences with Spain; need to send further instructions to Robinson now that Williamson has returned from the Hague. 1. Beeston, William, Sir, fl. 1702. 2. Darien, Scots' Colony. 3. Stanhope, Alexander, 1637?-1707. 4. Williamson, Joseph, Sir, 1633-1701. 5. Robinson, John, Bishop of London, 1650-1723.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jul 7
      About replacing Edmund Dummer as Surveyor of the Navy; an attack on several Irish counterfeiters; Tobacco contract with the Czar. 1. Dummer, Edmund. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Counterfeiters and counterfeiting--Great Britain. 4. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Russia. 5. Tobacco manufacture and trade--Russia.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jul 11
      Concerning the Irish counterfeiters in prison at Arnheim; warrant for bucks for Lord Mayor and Sheriffs; return of Williamson to London. 1. Counterfeits and counterfeiting-- Great Britain. 2. Williamson, Joseph, Sir, 1633-1701.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jul 14 (Box 9, Folder 199)
      News of Kidd the pirate. 1. Kidd, William, d. 1701.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jul 18
      Necessity of meeting costs of envoys; seizure of pirates from East Indies by Col. Blackistone; consideration of reward to one Turner for providing information against pirates. 1. Pirates. 2. Blackistone, Nathaniel, d. 1722.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jul 21
      Forwarding a letter on pirates in Pennsylvania. 1. Pirates.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jul 25
      Fitzgerald the counterfeiter; bucks for Eton at elections; Robinson and Swedish negotiations; a duel involving Count Dhona, envoy from Brandenburg. 1. Counterfeits and counterfeiting-- Great Britain. 2. Eton College. 3. Robinson, John, Bishop of London, 1650-1723. 4. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Sweden. 5. Great Britain-- Foreign relations--Brandenburg.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Jul 28
      Reports on Fitzgerald the counterfeiter by Sir William Gore and Dr. Newton (as Warder of the Mint); repercussions of the duel involving Brandenburg's envoy; pirates missed in Bristol. 1. Gore, William, Sir, d. 1707. 2. Newton, Isaac, Sir, 1642-1727. 3. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Brandenburg. 4. Pirates. 5. Blackistone, Nathaniel, d. 1722.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Aug 1 (Box 9, Folder 200)
      About preparing an answer to the Emperor's letter about his son's marriage; proposing Alexander Skene as Secretary of Barbados; Benbow's squadron in the West Indies. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Holy Roman Empire. 2. Skene, Alexander. 3. Barbados--Politics and Government. 4. Benbow, John, 1653- 1702. 5. Great Britain. Navy. 6. Darien. Scots' Colony.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Aug 4
      Fitzgerald the counterfeiter and the Bank of England's efforts to stop illegal coining; the case of Thomas Wray, involving fraud against the Treasury; report on Kidd. 1. Counterfeits and counterfeiting-- Great Britain. 2. Bank of England. 3. Heathcote, Gilbert, Sir. 4. Great Britain. Treasury. 5. Kidd, William, d. 1701.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Aug 8
      More on Count Dhona's duel. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Brandenburg.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Aug 11
      Report of seizure of 12 French Protestants off an English ship by officers of an armed French ship. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- France.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Aug 15
      About the seizure of an English ship off the coast of Guinea; Skene's warrant as secretary of Barbados. 1. Great Britain. Board of Trade and Plantations. 2. Africa--Commerce-- Great Britain. 3. Skene, Alexander.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Aug 18 (Box 9, Folder 200)
      Account of Board of Trade's deliberations on pirates and a militia in Pennsylvania; orders for Penn; warrant for Count Frise. 1. Great Britain. Board of Trade and Plantations. 2. Pirates. 3. Penn, William, 1644-1718. 4. Friesen, Julius Heinrich, Count von.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Aug 22
      Count Dhona's duel; Parliament prorogued until 28 Sep. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Brandenburg. 2. Stepney, George, 1663-1707. 3. Great Britain. Parliament, 1699.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Aug 25
      Urging Blathwayt to arrange approval for payment of Lord Paget's bills. 1. Paget, William Paget, 6th Baron, 1637-1713.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Aug 29
      Relays a report that Kidd surrendered to Bellamont in Boston. 1. Kidd, William, d. 1701. 2. Bellamont, Richard Coote, 1st Earl of, 1636-1701. 3. Pirates.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Sep 1
      Report on the securing of Kidd by Bellamont and moves by the Board of Trade to remove the Deputy Governor and Attorney General of Pennsylvania from office for their encouragement to pirates. 1. Kidd, William, d. 1701. 2. Bellamont, Richard Coote, 1st Earl of, 1636-1701. 3. Penn, William, 1644-1718. 4. Pennsylvania--History-- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775. 5. Pirates.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Sep 5 (Box 9, Folder 200)
      About Will O'Brian, a clipper of coins; settlement with Brandenburg, stemming from Count Dhona's duel; Paget's bills. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Brandenburg. 2. Paget, William Paget, 6th Baron, 1637-1713.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Sep 8
      Frigate to pick up Kidd; requests for passes. 1. Kidd, William, d. 1701. 2. Pirates.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Sep 12
      Reply to Czar's letter is being prepared; payment of envoys; O'Brian the clipper; Kidd. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Russia. 2. Kidd, William, d. 1701.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Sep 15
      Scots have quitted Darien. 1. Darien. Scots' Colony. 2. Beeston, William, Sir, fl. 1702.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Sep 19
      News; Paget's bills. 1. Paget, William Paget, 6th Baron, 1637-1713.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Sep 22
      Cover letter for Bellamont's report to Board of Trade about Kidd. 1. Bellamont, Richard Coote, 1st Earl of, 1636-1701.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Sep 26
      Concerning a proposal by Robinson to the Council of Trade. 1. Robinson, John, Bishop of London, 1650-1723. 2. Great Britain. Board of Trade and Plantations.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Sep 29 (Box 9, Folder 200)
      Reluctance to convey the King's request to the Spanish Ambassador to leave England. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Spain.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Oct 3
      Scots have quit Darien; Spanish Ambassador is making preparations for his departure. 1. Darien. Scots' Colony. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Spain.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Oct 6
      About his efforts to track down source of a false report in "Flying Post" about Darien settlers reaching New York. 1. Darien. Scots' Colony. 2. The Flying-Post: or the post-master.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1699 Oct 10
      About two cases pending before the Attorney General; departure of Spanish Ambassador. 1. Great Britain. Attorney General. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Spain.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1701 Aug 5
      About filling army commissions and settling instructions for Admirals Rooke and Benbow. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Rooke, George, Sir, 1650-1709. 4. Benbow, John, 1653- 1702.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1701 Aug 22
      Forwarding an account of the death of William Stoughton, Lt. Gov. of Massachusetts Bay and discussing a commission for one Mr. Hawks. 1. Stoughton, William, 1631-1701. 2. Great Britain. Army. 3. Massachusetts--History--Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775.
  - Villettes, Salomon de Vulston de
    - Document, signed., to the King of England, 1701 Oct 27 (Box 9, Folder 201)
      Reporting on the colonies of Vaudois near Frankfurt. Also signed by Jean Giraue, Pastor. 1. Great Britain. Sovereigns, etc., 1694-1701 (William III). 2. Waldenses.
  - Warre, Richard
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1702/3 Jan 30 (Box 10, Folder 202)
      Writing on behalf of Lord Nottingham to ask Blathwayt to order troops to look for two escaped prisoners of war. 1. Great Britain. Army. I. Nottingham, Daniel Finch, 2nd Earl of, 1647-1730.
  - Watts, Henry
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Deal, 1691 May 13
      Reporting on transport ships in the Down. 1. Great Britain. Navy.
  - Widdington, William Widdington, 3rd Baron, 1656?-1695
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], Berwick, 1686 Sep 26 (Box 10, Folder 203)
      Asking to be informed if he should come up to the parliament when his garrison is settled. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Great Britain. Parliament, 1686.
  - Willem, Hendrik I, Prince of Nassau, 1684-1718
    - ALS (in French) to William III, Liege, 1701 Oct 7
      Writing as Prince of Liege and expressing his support for the alliance against France. 1. William III, King of Great Britain, 1650-1702. 2. Great Britain- -Foreign relations--Liege.
  - Williamson, Joseph, Sir, 1633-1701
    - 4 ALS to William Blathwayt, The Hague, 1697/8 Mar 11-
      - Concerning subsidies for Denmark and, 1698 Aug 8
      - charities due to refugees. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Denmark.
  - Wolseley, Robert, 1649-1697
    - Letter (copy) to [William Blathwayt?], Brussels, 1693 Apr 17/27 (Box 10, Folder 204)
      Report of the commissioners of the Hospital concerning setting up a hospital for troops in Brussels; also signed by T. Venner and [Richard] Hill. 1. Great Britain. Army. I. Great Britain. Commissioners of the Hospital. II. Venner, T. III. Hill, Richard, 1655-1727.
  - Wolseley, William, 1640?-1697
    - 2 ALS to William Blathway, London, 1692 Aug 26
      - Acknowledging his being made master, 1694 Jul 10
      - of the Ordnance in Ireland, and explaining his petitions for grants of land in Ireland. 1. Great Britain. Army.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Dublin, 1697 Aug 19
      Explaining his petition for a grant of lands in Ireland. Accompanied by copy of the report on Wolseley's petition by Alan Brodrick, 1697 Sep 17, 8 pp. I. Midleton, Alan Brodrick, Viscount, 1660?-1728.
  - Wycke, Zachary
    - Last Will and Testament: contemporary ms. copy, Leominster, 1796 Jan 28 (Box 10, Folder 205)
      Gives the text of the codicils; apparently part of a legal report on his will. Wyke was a surgeon and apothecary.
  - Yard, Robert
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Jul 26 (Box 10, Folder 206)
      Reports on a meeting of the Lords Justices and on the parliamentary poll at Westminster. 1. Vernon, James, 1646-1727. 2. Halifax, Charles Montagu, 1st Earl of, 1661-1715. 3. Colt, Henry, Sir, d. 1731. 4. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 5. Great Britain. Parliament--Elections.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Jul 29
      Meeting of the Lords Justices; decision to send Capt. Warren to suppress piracy in the East Indies; consideration of three Irish bills; linen manufacture in Ireland; results of parliamentary elections, including Westminster. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Pirates. 3. Ireland. Parliament, 1698. 4. Ireland--Manufactures. 5. Great Britain. Parliament-- Elections. 6. Great Britain. Board of Trade and Plantations.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Aug 2
      Report from Lords Justices about the petitions of two outlawed Irishmen; consideration of Irish bills; news of elections, including London. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Ireland. Parliament, 1698. 3. Great Britain. Parliament-- Elections.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Aug 5
      Meeting of the Lords Justices; dispatch of squadrons; Irish linen manufacture bill; discussion of possible procedure of proroguing parliament; Irish bills; elections, including London. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Ireland-- Manufactures. 4. Great Britain. Board of Trade and Plantations. 5. Ireland. Parliament, 1698. 6. Great Britain. Parliament, 1698. 7. Great Britain. Parliament--Elections.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Aug 9 (Box 10, Folder 206)
      Meeting of Lords Justices; dispatch of squadrons and arrangements for paying seamen; victualling costs in Spain; prorogation of parliament; elections, including Oxford. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Pirates. 4. Great Britain. Treasury. 5. Bank of England. 6. Great Britain. Commissioners of Victualling. 7. Great Britain. Parliament, 1698. 8. Great Britain. Parliament-- Elections. 9. Musgrave, Christopher, 4th bart., 1632-1704.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Aug 12
      Meeting of the Lords Justices; orders and pay for Col. Brudenell's regiments; piracy in Madagascar. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Pirates.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Aug 16
      Meeting of Lords Justices; merchant relations with Genoa; consideration of a new charter for East India Company. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Genoa. 3. Blackwell, Lambert, Sir, d. 1727. 4. Aylmer, Matthew Aylmer, Baron, d. 1720. 5. East India Company (English).
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Aug 19 (Box 10, Folder 206)
      New charters for the General Society of the Subscribers to the Two Millions and for the East India Company; proroguing of parliament; Lord Jersey's travels. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. General Society of the Subscribers to the Two Millions. 3. East India Company (English). 4. Great Britain. Parliament, 1698. 5. Jersey, Edward Villiers, 1st Earl of, 1656-1711.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Aug 23
      Victually bills in Spain; suppression of pirates; payment of Aylmer's squadron; news of elections, including one in Norfolk which led to a duel. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Commissioners for Victualling. 3. Pirates. 4. Great Britain. Navy. 5. Aylmer, Matthew Aylmer, Baron, d. 1720. 6. Great Britain. Parliament--Elections. 7. Hobart, Henry, Sir, d. 1698.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Aug 26
      Lords Justices; Straits and West Indies squadrons. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Aylmer, Matthew Aylmer, Baron, d. 1720.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Aug 30 (Box 10, Folder 206)
      Aylmer's squadron and contingency plans in case of the King of Spain's death; West Indies squadrons; suppression of piracy; French prisoners taken by English in West Indies; attack on English ship in Lisbon. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Aylmer, Matthew Aylmer, Baron, d. 1720. 3. Great Britain. Navy. 4. Pirates. 5. Great Britain. Board of Trade and Plantations. 6. Great Britain--Foreign relations--France. 7. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Portugal.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Sep 2
      Possibility of sending orders to Admiral Aylmer to demand satisfaction from Republic of Genoa for its treatment of English merchants. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Aylmer, Matthew Aylmer, Baron, d. 1720. 3. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Genoa.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Sep 6
      Orders prepared for Aylmer's squadron, and Commissioners for Trade to draw up instructions for West Indies squadron; Irish bill; appointment of Christopher Montagu as Auditor of the Exchequer upon death of Sir Robert Howard. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Great Britain. Board of Trade and Plantations. 4. Aylmer, Matthew Aylmer, Baron, d. 1720. 5. Howard, Robert, Sir, 1626-1698. 6. Montagu, Christopher, d. 1735.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Sep 9 (Box 10, Folder 206)
      Consideration by Lords Justices of draft instructions for West Indies squadron prepared by Commissioners for Trade; petition of Henry Killigrew. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Great Britain. Board of Trade and Plantations. 4. Killigrew, Henry, d. 1712.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Sep 13
      Asking Blathwayt to help his nephew get a company in England. 1. Great Britain. Army.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Sep 13
      Acknowledging orders for Col. Collingwood's regiment to join West Indies squadron; treatment of English ships in Algiers. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Algiers.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Sep 16
      Naval matters. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Admiralty. 3. Great Britain. Navy.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Sep 20
      Plans for a mutual release of prisoners of war with the French; death of Christopher Codrington, governor of the Leeward Islands. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- France. Codrington, Christopher, d. 1698.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Sep 23
      West Indies squadron; further prorogation of Parliament. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Great Britain. Parliament, 1698. 4. Shovell, Clowdisley, Sir, 1650-1707.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Sep 27
      West Indies squadron and problems of desertion; prorogation of Parliament. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Great Britain. Army. 4. Great Britain. Parliament, 1698.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Sep 30
      Irish bills; election of Lord Mayor of London. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Ireland. Parliament, 1698. 3. London. Lord Mayor--Elections.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Oct 4 (Box 10, Folder 207)
      Col. Collingwood's regiment ordered to Portsmouth to prevent further desertions; Adm. Benbow also ordered to Portsmouth to see that the ships bound for the West Indies are ready to sail; Irish bills concerning the manufacture of linen and wool; bills referred to the Commissioner for Trade; polls for the Mayor of London. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Benbow, John, 1653-1702. 4. Ireland. Parliament, 1698. 5. London. Lord Mayor--Elections. 6. Child, Francis, Sir, 1642-1713.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Oct 7
      Need for a new ambassador to India; whether he should go there on naval or company ship; company will probably nominate Norris. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. East India Company (English). 3. Norris, William, Sir, 1657-1702.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Oct 11
      Lords Justices; West Indies squadron. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Navy.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Oct 14
      Nomination of Norris as ambassador to the Great Mogul; Irish bills. 1. East India Company (English). 2. Norris, William, Sir, 1657-1702. 3. Ireland. Parliament, 1698.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Oct 18
      Filling regiments for West Indies; Shovell and Channel Fleet. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Army. 3. Great Britain. Admiralty. 4. Shovell, Clowdisley, Sir, 1650-1707.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Oct 21
      Prorogation of Parliament; Channel fleet preparing to bring William III back; merchant passes for Algiers; West Indies squadron; new government for Leeward Islands. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Parliament, 1698. 3. Great Britain. Navy. 4. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Algiers. 5. Great Britain--Colonies--Leeward Islands.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Oct 25 (Box 10, Folder 207)
      Report of votes in the Irish House of Commons. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Ireland, Parliament, 1698. House of Commons.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Oct 28
      Prorogation of Parliament; Irish Parliament; "great stir" about 'An answer from a French officer'; readiness of channel fleet. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Parliament, 1698. 3. Ireland. Parliament, 1698. 4. "The Injured Protestant vindicated". 5. Great Britain. Navy.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Nov 1
      Setting date for sitting of Parliament; report on votes in Irish House of Commons. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Parliament, 1698. 3. Ireland. Parliament, 1698. House of Commons.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Nov 4
      Proclamation for sitting of Parliament. Report on Irish Parliament. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain. Parliament, 1698. 3. Ireland. Parliament, 1698.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Nov 8
      Report on Irish Parliament; Shovell and the King's convoy. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Ireland. Parliament, 1698. 3. Shovell, Clowdisley, Sir, 1650-1707.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Nov 11 (Box 10, Folder 207)
      Detailed report on a plot against the King's life as discovered by one Paul Robinson; Sec. Vernon's investigation; plot recognized as false; Robinson committed to Newgate. 1. Vernon, James, 1646-1727. 2. Robinson, Paul. 3. Brudenell, Francis, d. 1698.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Nov 15
      Robinson's plot; Genovese treatment of Englishmen; credentials for Norris are prepared; Irish Parliament; expectations from English Parliament. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Genoa. 3. Kirke, Thomas, 1650-1706. 4. Norris, William, Sir, 1657-1702. 5. East India Company (English). 6. Ireland. Parliament, 1698. 7. Great Britain. Parliament, 1698.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Nov 18
      Report on Irish Parliament. 1. Ireland. Parliament, 1698.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1698 Nov 22